good afternoon and welcome back everyone
to our options education webinar series
my name is Tony Zang I'm the chief
strategist here at options play and I am
honored to have two legends with me this
afternoon Tom saof from tasty trade and
tasty live uh and Brian Overby our
senior option strategist here at options
play gentlemen both
welcome thanks for having us Tony
awesome to be here Tony I'm excited to
get going with this session it's been a
long time since I've chatted with Tom
yeah um this is going to be a fun
session to be perfectly honest we'll get
through a lot about both of you a little
bit of your history we'll talk markets
and also talk option strategies we'll
kind of cover the full basis um just a
reminder for those of you that are
joining us for the first time every
single Thursday afternoon we are
dedicated here at options play to
helping you improve your options
creating by empowering you to trade
sustainably and confidently by doing
these options education sessions and
cover a wide variety of topics not just
options trading but technical analysis
fundamental analysis uh trading
psychology and have guests like Tom snof
with bu over to kind of discuss option
strategies and bring a different
perspective um so during today's session
what we are going to discuss here today
is purely for education and
demonstration purposes it is not a
solicitation or recommendation to buy or
sell any of the specific securities that
we might use as example purposes during
today's session so we'll be covering uh
quite a bit but what I'll do is I'll
start off by giving both Tom and Brian
uh a bit of time to introduce themselves
for those of you who may not know who
they are um and then we'll talk a little
bit about the current market environment
which is a bit of a strange environment
and kind of ask both Brian and and Tom
how they would think about trading this
type of Market environment and then what
we're going to do is we're going to pick
their brains we're going to ask them
what their number one options strategy
is what do they trade most often and
kind of get a better sense for best
practices for order entry order exit I'm
going to take notes as we go along as
they kind of share with you those uh
their favorite strategy and we will make
sure we incorporate those notes and send
them out with recording um and at the
very end we'll let Tom uh walk us
through the tasty trade um platform as
he walks through some of the trades that
he's he likes to trade and then we'll
open this up for Q&A here at the very
end and I'll show you also how to uh set
up a tasty trade account for those of
you who that do not have one just yet so
let's start off um Tom you know we've
been doing this quite a few times but
for those of you that are joining us
perhaps for the first time first of all
I see you know hundreds of you in the
chat room already chiming in so please
if you're joining us for the first time
feel free to type a hello into the chat
window and tell us who you are where
you're from um as you can see we have a
very Vibrant Community of Traders um
that are here to support each other and
learn from each other um but you know
for those of you that don't know I have
been doing this for roughly 19 years and
I started trading options watching Tom
uh host webinars on The Thinker swim
platform 19 years ago you know I still
remember sitting at my desk on Wall
Street being looking at that options
chains page and being confused as to
what I was looking at and just watching
Tom every single day showing us how to
trade that's why I'm here today um and
honestly Brian Overby you were with Tom
at that time so watching the two of you
learn how to trade options from the two
of you it's it's um it's fantastic to
bring It full circle and be able to
interview both of you on on options
trading so first of all Tom I just want
to give you an opportunity to uh
tell everyone for those who don't know
who you are a little bit about your
background and um um and then Brian I'll
I'll do the same for you afterwards all
right sure happy to I mean you know
um I love that intro because it makes it
does make me feel a little old which I
don't like you know but makes me feel
like I've been around a while but I have
been around a while like like over 40
years doing this uh in this business 20
years as a market maker
and um and almost now uh 20 20 actually
19 years as a market maker and 25 years
um uh building thinker swim and then
building tasty trade and you know so a
lot of history on the market making side
of the business a lot of history on the
software development side and and the
content development side for the last 14
years along with software but it's funny
you know um when you told me that Brian
you know joined your team I was like
holy cow like I haven't I I think a
couple years ago Brian and I did a
seminar together for somebody um at some
event but I haven't seen Bri it was Dan
Sheridan oh yeah Dan Sheran right a
couple years ago and um there was there
was a time you know I was like um Brian
and I have always stayed in contact
throughout the years I think I tried to
get him to come back to to Tasty or
something at one point and uh you were
kind of you know you you had moved out
of state and and you know listen Life Is
Life is weird that way but I remember
when Brian was an instructor at the at
the sibo and and correct me if I'm wrong
because this this we're talking like 23
24 years ago Brian but I think you were
an instructor at the sibo and you're
working for um The Exchange and um we
convinced you to come on over and run
education for us at at thinker swim and
we had a we had a really nice run until
some firm scarfed you and uh to build
their platform out so um but uh and you
told me at the time the name of the firm
and I mentioned that too Tom what you
know we kind of brought it up a little
bit but yeah it was options Planet way
back in the day and it didn't last that
long under that name but I remember we
were doing an education platform and you
we needed to separate church and state
the education wanted to be separate from
the actual brokerage firm to try to keep
finra happy but yeah that was 20 some
years ago uh honestly yeah scary thought
yeah so our paths have we've we've
crisscrossed you know throughout the
years in um different stuff and um
different educational events and and
things like that so we've you know
always always maintained friendship the
funny thing about this business is he
can never burn any Bridges you know he
always it's amazing it's a small
incestuous business and and uh everybody
seems to come full circle like you said
Tony and uh when you said Brian was
going to be on this webinar today I'm
like oh that's cool you know we haven't
done something together in a while and
um I don't know if we still think
exactly alike or um but we definitely
bring you know very um our own personal
kind of stories and um and our own
personal methodology you know to the uh
to the game and so I think that's kind
of cool and um listen as long as we give
quick takeaways today and people get a
lot out of this it's gonna be a great
day so let's make it happen excellent I
agree thank you um Brian a little bit of
your background for those who may not
know who you are yeah well Tom did a
pretty good job of of summing it up um
worked for a few brokerage firms but the
the the times that I remember the most
some of my Fondest Memories Tom where
like way back in the day it was myself
and actually when I first did my first
event with options play somebody brought
up Don koffman's name so we were the
first two instructors uh with options
Planet way way back when and one of the
favorite things that I used to do and I
still have fond memories of is traveling
to Vegas and actually doing trading
shows I think it was once a quarter or
so maybe a little bit more frequent than
that and a little bit more little bit
more frequent but we gotta be careful
getting into those stories because that
could go on we could tell about five
hours of stories here and we can scare
the children but um what I was actually
telling the story the other day that we
were doing a show in Vegas back in like
2002 or I think it was 2002 and we
started the show on a Friday morning at
4:30 in the morning and there were
people online going into rain the
nightclub and the nightclub line snaked
around the whole building at 4:30 in the
morning and we're going in to start
trading options to make the opening at 6
o'clock into the ballroom and that's how
crazy a scene that was back in the early
2000s so um yeah good memory yeah and
it's amazing how many people would show
up live that that is the kind of where I
was going every single one of those
events we would have hundreds if not
thousands that would come in even just
to see me I I used to do demonstrations
of the platform back then and just
amazing how many people would show up
live for those events uh it's it was
very
impressive yeah so both you know what
I'd like to just ask start this off with
a bit of a fun question here um you know
you guys have obviously been in this
industry for a long time what has change
what from your perspective has surprised
you in terms of change in this industry
that you never thought would happen and
what hasn't changed since you've started
I'll let Tom go because he obviously has
the seniority in this
situation well you know I think
Tony the I think maybe I'm not as
surprised by this but I think that to
answer your
question the I never thought that we
would see a time when derivatives based
on Capital efficiency would dominate the
trading landscape so so right now you
know at most of the online brokerage
firms not all but most when I say most I
mean you know everybody from tasty to
interactive brokers to thinker swim to
Robin Hood um the marketplace is
dominated by the derivative side even
erade um to a certain extent even
Fidelity and um you're seeing you know
the stock trading account for maybe in
most cases 20% of all the retail volume
max
25% and the rest is really derivatives
and it's because people understand how
important Capital efficiency is
today so I don't think that 20 years ago
when we started the amount of
derivatives business that TD Merit trade
did was about 8% of their total business
and so the thing that I I think I feel
most proud of is kind of changing the
landscape of individual self-directed
investors moving from kind of very
static um very static Equity Investments
you know not necessarily passive but
like static and day trading that kind of
stuff into a world of strategic
investing that is highly leveraged
Capital efficient and very
strategic thank you thank you for that
Insight um Brian well yeah and and I
still even I mean one one of the things
that that Tom did and and and his whole
company back in the day is make it all
about education and make it about uh uh
knowing that option Traders Want to Talk
Amongst each other like Tom has
mentioned it's a very tight group and uh
one of the biggest things that we'd
focus on is just like trading groups uh
there were people in libraries all
across the US way back in the day that
would always get together and talk about
option trading and that has really been
steadfast as far as uh that whole group
of people and how much you know it's
like getting together so almost I'd
almost equate it to how fantasy football
made the NFL what it's made I mean all
the option Traders always get together
and the fact that it's getting easier
and easier to do that is a big reason
why there's so much growth in that
space yeah well um let's jump right into
it then let's talk a little bit about
the current markets and you know I'm I'd
like to ask both of your opinion on this
because I actually don't remember last
time where we saw S&P 500 at all-time
highs like this and the vix trading
above 20% you know well off the lows you
know Tom what's your take on kind of why
we're seeing this Dynamic and how do you
actually trade this type of
Market well there's no question that um
there
is uh this would be considered you know
if you told me that we were making
all-time highs um I would have given you
a vix Market of probably like 135 you
know would have been my two-sided market
so you're right the Vick's up above 20
um part of it's a reflection on just you
know things that are happening um with
respect to interest rates right now
things that are happening with respect
to the election coming up I'm sure that
all is a part of it but the also the
strangest thing about this Market that I
can remember the strange thing about
this new high is that there's also a
crazy amount
of um protection being bought and there
are a lot of people that feel
differently about this being a new high
than I've seen in the past usually you
get an incredible amount of complacency
when the market makes new highs and
that's why volatility gets so cheap this
time around we're not seeing any of the
complacency in fact what we're seeing is
an expansion of fear and you know as as
you can tell witnessed by a very high
skew witnessed by just incredibly large
amount of put volume especially in the
especially in the index products um I
think there's a certain preparedness for
some kind of you know um uh downside
risk or downside velocity that we
usually don't see at Market highs and so
I mean to be fair I think that bodess
pretty well for the market as a
contrarian but the other side of it is I
just don't think we've seen this very
often it is not typical that the market
is prep cared for something ugly to
happen at alltime highs that's just not
normal yeah Brian thoughts yeah well you
know we had uh hotter than than expected
CPI and then you also come in and you
see you know the the debate about Jobs
versus inflation where is that taking us
to seeing the vix at this High which
seasonally you know going back 20 years
or so uh September and October have been
ex you know just in General higher
volatile months but to me with the
market at an all-time high yeah once
again I you just don't anticipate that
so you know you're talking about a trade
that we like to do in a market like this
is I've actually been trading Vick's
options and one of the things and this I
kind of meant to say this when we were
talking about things that you didn't
expect I was actually on the retail
markets committee for the Chicago Board
option exchange and when they talked
about trading vix options I I was dead
wrong I said there's no way that people
would understand them and that the
product wouldn't take off um that that
was my uh opinion back then but
obviously I've been I was dead wrong on
that and that it's uh had extremely
great volumes and I I like to trade the
vix in September in October and I I like
to put get together strategies there's
so much volatility in the options
contracts it's just kind of fun to come
up to me it's a fun index to trade
especially when you have situations
where you're at an all-time high and
you're seeing the vix up around that 20
Level so do you see like Tom this as a
bit of a contrarian uh event where this
potentially could be a positive for for
equities can you guys hear me yeah we
can I can hear you was that question to
Brian or me oh yeah that was that was a
question to Brian I was asking Brian if
he also sees this uh this Market dynamic
as a cont as a as a bit of a contrarian
that's positive for equities you know
with a vix at 20 but we're at all-time
highs is the market maybe over
anticipating or maybe overly fearful um
about downside risk well you know I we
got the big unknown event or known event
that's happening in in November and I do
think that the market wants to get past
the election before it decides which way
it's going to go and I and I feel like
that has a little and and that's the
thing about the vix is it's really just
a feel scenario that that has a little
bit of the reason why we're seeing the
vix at these high levels and I'm not
necessarily saying that uh you know
whoever wins the
election the Market's going to go up or
down I just think that known event needs
to go away uh interest rates obviously
uh are are a huge uh Dynamic that's in
this Marketplace too that hasn't always
been the case where the FED is looking
to possibly do four Cuts over the next
year and after this huge runup that
we've had in interest rates so just
those little Dynamics and you throw in
the obvious the geopolitical concerns I
do think the market wants to go higher
they just want a reason to to do it and
they need to get rid of some of these
speed bumps in the road just like uh Tom
was mentioning how just put premiums are
are skyrocketing which is obviously the
driver of the vix at this point in time
but in general we're coming into
earnings you know we're kicking off
earnings with JP Morgan and Wells Fargo
and the financials tomorrow and I really
think that those are going to be very
interesting earnings reports and and
just actually their opinion after uh
after the big event after their their
earnings announcements and and uh I
think the mark So in general to sum it
up I think the market wants to go higher
it needs to get past the election and
get a little bit more feel as to what
the FED is planning on doing going into
2025 that's simple thank you thank you I
appreciate that so let's jump into kind
of the
the the part that I think we're all here
for which is I'd like to ask both of you
what's the number one option strategy
you trade in your portfolio what
strategy do you trade most often and
then we'll kind of get into rules that
you have around entry and exit and then
if you want to go through some examples
Tom with using the tasty trade plat
platform feel free to do so but let's
start off by what's the number one
option strategy that you use most often
in your portfolio and if you can tell us
a little bit as far as
why sure you want me to start I will um
yeah
so I guess I would Define myself Tony as
a premium seller I think I always have
been um let me put this say I always
have been as a retail investor as a as a
self-directed do-it-yourself or I've
always been a premium seller and um uh
so that that that puts me into a certain
category of strategies um and I would
say that I'm lean towards about 75%
undefined risk and about 25% toine risk
if I looked at all the different things
that I
do excuse
me sorry um so bless you given given
that um I'm 75% undefined risk and 25%
defined risk and most of my defined risk
trades I would argue are are probably
like iron condors and and straight you
know short verticals um just one half of
an iron counter that would be most of my
defined risk trades so most of my
undefined risk trades the majority and
again I do almost every strategy so I
don't want to like make it seem like I'm
a one-trick Pony um because most days I
still average about a 100 trades a day
so I would say that I the majority of my
trades are short strangles um because I
don't tend to sell one side I might
ratio the strangle but for the most part
I am a strangle seller just outside of
the expected move and so that tends to
be I'm a high volatility strangle seller
just outside of expected move so Tony
you we've talked about this kind of many
times I look at Ivy rank I choose my I
choose my strikes outside of the
expected move I sometimes skew them a
little bit just based on my own opinion
of you know whatever price extreme is
and I tend to go out um at least one
full cycle ideally I'd like to be out at
45 days but it could be 35 days it could
be 50 days but 45 days is a sweet spot
at my cycle so 45 days out just outside
the expected move which is like around
the 20-ish Delta on both sides
skew it a little bit if you're a little
bit bullish or a little bit bearish give
it a little bit of skew and um and stay
relatively small and put on lots of
underlyings and only trade things with
high implied volatility
rank perfect so let me just summarize
this um I think you made it clear you
trade a pretty wide variety of
strategies but you certainly lean
towards premium selling and within that
premium selling you're doing
predominantly strangles some some some
iron condor credit spreads and then when
it comes to strangles you're going out
roughly 45 days uh and we can talk a
little bit about as far as why that's
the case as far as strike prices go
you're selling just outside of that
expected move which you can also think
you know similar to one standard
deviation roughly 20 deltas and you are
doing it across um single stock I'm
guessing both single stock and index uh
with that that have high IV rank is that
a good summation of kind of what we've
that's fair I actually I'm indifferent
to product there are a couple things
that I don't sell premium in I don't
sell premium in volatility underlyings
um that's where Brian and I might differ
a little bit I don't sell volatility
underlyings I don't sell premium in
biotechs and I do use the same exact
strategies in Futures options as well so
I don't limit myself to just Equity
options so my scope is is I like highly
liquid underlyings because that's really
important to me so I guess there's
probably about maybe 10 to 12 different
Futures options that I trade and
probably let's call it 70 to 80
different equities that I trade and I'm
including indexes with those equities so
ETFs indexes and
equities and and I think
one detail that I think is incredibly
important to the success of the strategy
that you mentioned that may have just
been that slip through is the fact that
you said that you keep your size small
but you do it on a lot of underlines at
the same time
I'm a I'm a big believer in so so I I
have a couple things that I that I live
kind of by as a Trader one is I'm an
efficient market freak so I believe that
prices are relatively efficient if you
stick with liquid underlyings so I don't
worry about you know macro stuff and
geopolitical events and things like that
because I feel like everything's built
in to the market you know that sense but
I also have learned over the years that
there's a couple of aspects of trading
that are really important to achieving
your objective and one of them is
creating enough occurrences so that
essentially you know the law of large
numbers kind of plays out in your favor
and I find that when I try to be very
selective and trade larger I do um I I
don't do nearly as well as when I trade
smaller and I'm less selective because I
have to recognize that I really even
though I have maybe a personal opinion
on something it doesn't really mean
anything because I don't you know I'm
not necessarily right more than I'm
wrong when I'm guessing Market
Direction and I think that's an
incredibly important detail on on you
know the the success of this strategy is
that as you said the the law of large
numbers and I think this is a concept
that a lot of retail Traders may not
necessarily have a good grasp on and I
think this is something worth exploring
for those of you that are maybe hearing
this for the first time of trying to
grasp that concept of what it means to
trade small but spread that trade spread
the trades across a large number of
underlines especially in strategies like
this where you're selling premium and
you're collecting premium and you're
effectively trying to
um uh you know effectively trade the the
mean reversion of volatility here um so
thank you so much for sharing that Tom
can I just also ask you on kind of trade
management so let's let's talk about
this 45 day 20 Delta strangle um how do
you think about how do you manage those
trades
do you hold them to expiration do you
manage them what's your what's your
thought process another one of the one
of the byproducts of so so tasty is a
think tank the the content part of our
business is a think tank I know Brian
used the word education before but I I
like to think of Education being very
static you know you and I have talked
about this before and I like to think
about like the stuff that you do and the
stuff that we do it's it's it's much
more content because it's always it's
always Dynamic it's always flowing and I
think that um
uh with respect to the content and the
research that we've done over the last
decade uh one of the things that one of
our biggest takeaways is that if you
manage the trades early that's about
let's call it halfway through the life
cycle so I manage everything at 21 DTE
so if I put it on at 45 I manage a 21
roll to the next month by doing that
you're living in the optimal part of the
Decay curve and you're also virtually
eliminating your outlier risk you're not
eliminating your risk at all you're
eliminating your outlier risk
and because most outlier risk happens in
the last you know week or two weeks when
you're kind of when you get these gamma
explosions and things like that so my
focus is manage early eliminate the
outlier risk and you know kind of live
in The Sweet Spot of that decay
curve and just just so let's kind of
just there's two parts that I want to
ask you right when you refer to The
Sweet Spot of the K curve what I'm
resuming you're you're saying here is
that that's really where you're getting
a good amount of theta Decay but you
don't have much gamma risk yet um once
you kind of cross 21 days that's when
yes Theta is faster but gamma risk
actually starts to kind of work against
that your spoton from 45 to 21 days is
The Sweet Spot and what happens what's
really interesting when you look at the
numbers and you look at your p&l per day
and you look at it's basically this is a
theoretical discussion but when you look
at your theoretical p&l per day your
theoretical p&l per day from 45 days to
21 days is higher than it is from 21
days down to zero and what's so
fascinating about that is your Decay
accelerates as you get closer to zero
but your theoretical p&l actually goes
down so when you look at it and you
think well why would I take more risk to
make less money I would rather live in
the part of the cycle where I'm taking
less risk to make more money and and
that's one of the biggest takeaways that
we've learned and that we've researched
like extensiv like like literally
hundreds of thousands of hours over the
last you know 14
years and you know what's interesting is
that you know over the last 14 years the
the concentration of of strategies is
now predominantly in you know seven days
or less right what I think close to 50%
of volume now is is traded in in
strategies that are seven days from
expiration or or shorter it's really
wild and um you know it it's a
fascinating thing because the zero days
are and the zero days and the seven days
and and inside of that are are really
interesting from from many perspectives
they're interesting from a brokerage
perspective because you know the one
thing we like about running a brokerage
firm the one thing we like about the
zero days is that we don't have any
overnight risk so so that's a that's a
kind of the the the subtle good part of
the zero days the bad part about the
seven days and in is that statistically
it's it's it's a lot of you know um it's
a lot of risk one to make some multiple
of one but it also has a much lower
probability of success so there's a much
lower success rate for individual
investors when you trade seven days and
in so the challenge and and again
another really big challenge about
trading short-term options is you want
to manage those TR early so if you're
doing like a 5-day trade you do not want
to let that trade go more than two two
and a half days if you're doing a
two-day trade you don't want to let that
trade go to the second day and if you're
doing a one- day trade and you put it on
in the morning you don't want to let
that trade go past noon like there's
this whole there's this whole kind of um
Universe of information of data of all
the statistics that we've been able to
grind out um and it's it's super
fascinating you know we have 18 months
now of zero Z day data and managing
early in the first half of the day is
just incredibly the results are
incredibly different than holding to the
close um so that brings me to the last
part of my question about your 45 days
strangle strategy you said you manage a
21 days expiration do you ever close
prior to that based on of course a
stoploss level or a takeprofit level of
course in fact the default for every
single person listening today should be
the default is always to close earlier
like if you're thinking if it's if it's
a no-brainer you're like I I like this
position I want to hold it fine go ahead
but if the decision is should I take
this profit or should I not our default
is to always take the profit adjust the
trade roll it hedge it we're super
aggressive in that regard because the
markets today if you're Trading
underlyings the markets are so efficient
that you're only giving up a penny or
two and just to learn how to take
profits to learn how to make those
trades the more times you do something
the better you get at decision-making
you know you and I have talked about
this so much in the past you know the
quicker you process stuff the quicker
you redeploy um I just feel like it's
you know the default is always better to
do something sooner than
wait perfect thank you so much um so
Brian let's switch over let's switch
gears over to you what is your number
one strategy that you use in your
portfolio and if you could share us with
us a little bit as far as why well I'm
gonna let Tom have the the short spreads
and the uh basically selling premium
overall and I was going to kind of uh
address this a little bit by just
talking about a trade that I did in the
vix recently uh using a butterfly on
things that have high volatility um
where you want to play a direction and I
usually like to try to modify that trade
now I can do one of two things Tom's
talking a little bit about short spreads
uh and I know that he uh I don't want to
put words in his mouth at all but I I
know that if he were looking at
butterflies a lot of times you're trying
to do them for a net credit trying to
bring in a like a skip strike butterfly
or a modified butterfly in that instance
and I've heard him I've just I've
listened to Tom for for years and years
and years but uh you know so I I like to
call it a skip strike butterfly if I'm
looking at a butterfly and I'll just
kind of leave it in this range and I
want to talk about the the the couple of
Trades that I've done recently in the
vix is uh if I look at a skip strike
butterfly I'm really embedding a call
spread to pay for a standard butterfly
and I like to look at it that way and
that's why in The Playbook I wrote uh
when I put the strategy together I
called it a skip strike butterfly
instead of a modified butterfly because
you're already embedding your hedge into
the trade if I'm short a spread and the
market starts coming uh towards my short
strike on the put side or on the call
side of things if you can get it done
for a decent net credit to the account
you're already got some protection into
the trade and I'm willing to stay into
that trade a little bit longer uh hoping
that maybe I'm I'm doing it based off of
a support or a resistance level so
that's kind of my way to approach doing
short spreads from time to time
everything always depends on the
underlying stock um but like recently I
looked at the vix going into September
and October and I've never and maybe Tom
canine on this a little bit but I've
never known the rationale behind why
September and October over the last 20
years looking at the calendar usually
the vix trades at higher levels just in
general uh it's you know it's it's a
fact by looking at the data uh from way
back from going all the way back to yeah
last 20 years was the last uh uh uh
last time I put all the research
together so with that said going into
September literally uh the last day in
August I put on a modified butterfly
where I like to uh the long side of the
butterfly because it's made up of a long
spread and a short spread the long
spread is wider than the short spread
and uh you can call it a weird butterfly
that to me that's a true modified
butterfly meaning that if the market
took off you're in the VIX Index and it
skyrocketed like it did in early August
you're still okay on that trade you're
still profitable on that trade so I you
know to to you know Tom obviously went
to the N degree talking about uh selling
premium and all that this is one trade
that I kind of like like even back in
the day uh you know butterflies were a
way that you price options make sure
that all your chains were correct
because there's such an efficient Str
strategy by looking at them and rolling
into going from a long spread turning it
into a butterfly going from a short
spread and and uh or going from a a
butterfly and turning it into a short
spread these are some adjustments that I
like to make in my trading and uh that's
one strategy that was a strategy that I
did recently when you asked me this
question and thought about that turned
out that worked really well Market was
at 16 put on the 18 sold the middle
strike around 26 and then modified it in
case the market took off and literally
the the first day in September you know
the market the market the vixs
skyrocketed and it seemed to do that
again in October so I I I would like to
know why is that what what are your
thoughts Tom on why do we get into
September and October and the vix seems
to just take
off I really don't have have a feel for
it a lot of memories maybe you know I
mean that's true a lot of Mondays in
October probably right yeah I mean you
know October 19th is 1987 has stuck with
me forever it was kind of the first I
mean it was the first kind of um Earth
shaking moment for me in this business
um uh the mini crash in 1989 the um
October 2008 you know was was an
absolutely brutal meltdown and I think
that when you just you know I I I I
think
a lot of Traders have some of those
dates dates just kind of ingrained in
their head but um the reality of October
expiration or October first as a as as
one of the most volatile months it's
actually not even the most volatile
month um it's crazy but like April and
July I think are are actually more
volatile than October September might
even be more volatile in history than
October which is kind of nuts and when
you look at October expirations going
back like the last 26 years I think um
because we always think of October
expiration you know kind of that 19th
20th of October is crazy but the reality
is 14 of the last 26 have been up TW uh
you know 12 have been down so it's kind
of like a really mixed bag but we all
have these memories of like you know
October 19th October 17th you know
October 22nd and and um so I think you
know I I just think it's more like you
know the shock value of some of those
crazy you know vix moves and I mean the
the three of the in the last 35 years or
whatever it is you know three of the
greatest vixs moves getting over 80 or
getting over close to 100 have always
come in October and I think that's it
Brian yeah yeah and and and I would
agree that that's just basically my
feeling and the way that I look at it
you know we got earnings that always
comes in uh usually this time of year
and you know we're about ready to kick
off that earning season um but you know
the big unknown event once again is is
the election so so that that's one way
that I like I I do agree with uh Tom
selling premium going out 45 days allows
you to adjust the trade uh if I'm doing
butterflies I'm going to do them shorter
term because you do want the time Decay
to work with you but you're kind of
putting your hedge in and that's what I
meant by if I'm looking at a shorter
term uh short call spread or short put
spread maybe think about a skip strike
butterfly uh cuz it's does give you the
protection before you go into the trade
but it's really all about the volatility
of that underlying that you're trading
and if you can go a decent amount away
from where the underlying stock is at
and get a credit by making it a skip
strike butterfly and I'll I'll leave it
there
Tony so let me ask you a clarification
on this right um if let's say you have a
bullish view on a stock and you're
trading a butterfly versus a bear stock
on the same on a different stock that
you're trading a butterfly are you using
called butterflies put butterflies iron
butterflies what type of butterflies are
you using specifically well yes uh
you're going to Target it you want to
trade the the lower price option
contract so if you are bullish on on the
uh underlying that you're trading you're
going to use calls you're going to go
out of the money you're going to Target
a a certain point uh where you might do
use some charting you might use some
technical analysis to come up with that
and then obviously on the other side of
the coin you're going to do that also
with put butterflies and one of the
bigger things too is that I I I have a
tendency to if if I want to be uh
bullish on something uh implied
volatility you want to come in if you're
correct on your forecast so if you're
buying a butterfly out of the money and
you're correct on your forecast you are
hoping implied volatility will go down
on that call side of things and that
will help out the butterfly when it's
all said and done but butterflies aren't
all about home runs right you're you're
you're uh you're putting them on uh
hoping that uh the you pay a dollar for
a butterfly and you can sell it for two
like that's the that's the way that
you're going to trade those positions
and and even usually we'll make one
adjustment if I'm doing some type of
butterfly too in that trade right so you
mentioned that you use shorted dated
expirations roughly how far out do you
like to go for your butterflies well it
would depend on on the underlying but
let's use the SPX for an example um I
want to probably stay with i a lot of
times when I was really first started
trading uh even even long spreads uh on
and would roll that into a butterfly as
a chip in a chair trade I don't want the
cheese anymore just let me out of the
Trap scenario uh look at five days put
it on on a Monday get out on a Friday uh
that simple uh in the vix trade that we
just talked about uh did it you the vix
the only option contracts that I really
like to trade that are liquid enough are
the ones that actually expire uh the
normal monthly expiration the third uh
Wednesday of the month so that was an
18-day trade in the vix um and like that
would be the maximum that I would want
to go out on a trade where you got a lot
of volatility in that
underlying great and lastly how do you
think about generally managing
these well uh you know that it's hard to
hard to go about without an example but
uh it like in the vix if I did a bearish
put butterfly and let's say the market
moved about 2% against me over that week
uh I like to then close the the most
expensive option contract and actually
roll it into a short put spread and get
bearish on the market and that's once
again just following the trend and it's
one adjustment the market turns on me I
get out right away but it gives me an
opportunity to put the trade on okay I
was wrong the market is going the other
direction let's sell sell the most
expensive option contract and buy the
least expensive option contract bringing
in a net credit to the account still
giving me a chance to be profitable and
now I am in a short spread position a
bullish position and we recently did a
little bit of that in in the education
here on options play not that long ago
so there is a webinar out there that
that we chat about it a little bit
in perfect and we'll link to that in the
recording so Tom I want to give you an
opportunity to kind of bring up the
tasty trade platform form and maybe go
let's go through an example of a
strangle um that you might sell on
perhaps a single stock that you've
identified something with a relatively
High implied volatility you know how you
set up that that strangle um in the TC
trade platform and just let's go through
a real example if we if you don't
mind okay so I'm GNA go to
share
yeah um let me make sure that you can
share one
second uh you should be able to
share I should be able to right here
let's see and I want to go to
application window and
share how's that
uh yep we could see it okay let me just
get rid of this so I can get rid of
this
um okay perfect
um let me get rid of these pictures
beautiful okay sorry about that I just
wanted to get it all set up so you can
see so this is kind of the basic you
know this is the basic tasty platform I
we have a very um straightforward simple
interface um the tasty platform for
people have never used it it's the only
retail platform that's built on pure
highfrequency middleware so it's super
fast super easy to use stock options
Futures Futures options everything
trades from the same interface crypto
everything but what I did here for you
is just bring up to give an example of
what I talked about with Tony I just
brought up Tesla and the reason I
brought up Tesla is if we want to talk
about the most liquid underlyings um
Tesla and Nvidia are probably the two
most liquid Equity underlyings I think
that's fair right Tony Tech Tesla and
Nvidia in my opinion are the two most
liquid underlyings um also Tesla has a
binary event tonight um which is why I
brought it up so so you can um uh so it
it was really active say Nvidia was
active as well but um I thought I'd
start with Tesla because they have a
like kind of their Robo taxi binary
event something later on tonight so
there was a lot of Premium jacked into
Tesla and one of the things I mentioned
when I talked to Tony about you know
what do I look for the first thing I
said was I look for liquidity and
obviously Tesla has huge liquidity this
is just after after hours volume here of
you know over two million shares but it
I don't even know how many I probably
traded 100 million plus shares today in
addition to that you can see the IV rank
here is 80
82.3 so what that means is on a scale of
1 to 100 ranking it's at the 82 83rd
kind of level and or number which means
that's close to as high as it gets now
occasionally like just to give you an
example of just showing us some stuff
with crazy high implied volatility
because we're in one of those times like
crude oil has a
99% implied volatility rank right now
that's about as high as you get but
those are Futures options so let's go
back to listed Equity options because
these you can get a little smaller on
and this is Tesla so the way the tasty
platform is set up over here this is
kind of just these are all just Futures
markets you these are obviously by
choice I this drop down menu is called
Tom's default so you could actually
anybody can get it and I just list the
equity Futures and this Tesla would be
in the NASDAQ futures and there's just a
bunch of other Futures here and then if
you scroll down there's lots of stocks
and things like that we built the whole
platform around watch list mentality but
like I mentioned to Tony I want High
implied volatility rank 82 is obviously
just about as high as you get I want
huge volume and this stock has massive
volume I want stocks that have high
implied volatility and this stock has an
an IV now this is not IV rank but an IV
of about 70 which is very high because
when you think about a 70 implied
volatility what you're really looking at
a 19% implied volatility is about a 1%
move a day so when you have a 70%
implied volatility you're talking about
an average daily move of about 3 and a
half% and on a $250 stock you know
you're up there in that 75 to $10 range
just based on implied volatility on a
daily basis the other thing that's cool
about the tasty platform is we show you
what the expected move is now I don't
have all the strikes listed here but if
I push them all up here you can see that
the Tesla one day just because the
binary event tomorrow the expected move
overnight is
$14.30 which is much higher than the
regular average daily move because you
can see here the implied volatility for
just for one day is 130 or something so
that's because there's a binary event
coming but when I make trades I like to
go out about 45 days so in this case I
went to closest to 45 days which is
November options which are in this case
36 days out and the first thing I look
at is the expected move 36 days out
which is 36 or
$37 now when you have a binary event
coming you're looking for something kind
of you know with heightened volatility
and you want to take advantage of
potentially that that extremely High
binary event premium or that event based
premium what I did and I did this very
late in the day because I was just kind
of fooling around in Tesla I went out to
November options I opened them up and I
said well if the expected move is 36 or
$37 to November I'm going to go twice
the expected move just to give myself a
little cushion a lot of cushion so I
went out and you can see right here
because these are just some small Tesla
positions we have on I sold a 20 lot of
the 17 puts 170 puts and the stock
closed to just about $240 they're $70
out of the money so they're just about
two times the expected move to the
downside and then to the upside I sold
the 350 calls which
are 350 calls are $120 out of the money
now the reason you can do that for
basically the same amount of money is
because these are these were
$135 these were a135 they were the exact
same price and the reason you could do
is because in Tesla the market perceives
the risk to be to the upside the
velocity of risk to be upside the market
does not saying the Stock's going to go
higher it's not saying that at all what
the Market's saying is if the stock does
go higher it will go higher faster than
if it goes lower I know that seems a
little weird but it's called it's called
pricing skew option pricing skew and all
the Market's saying is the velocity of
risk is to the upside it's not saying
that there's a better chance the stock
goes up than goes down it just says if
if it goes up it's going to go up faster
than if it goes down and because of that
I was able to sell this spread and
actually I was able to sell because I
sold a few minutes before the close at
$22.71 now is that a good trade I don't
know we'll see tomorrow um maybe it
comes in and I also have another
strangle on here too so in total I have
two different strangles on in Tesla and
they're both basically the same kind of
positions they're delta neutral meaning
there's zero Deltas to this trade now
that's almost exactly what I explained
to Tony before when we talked about
favored strategies except in this case
I'm doing it um I'm doing it around a
binary event so this is one strangle we
have on the other one we're short the
320 calls and we're short the 190 puts
so I have a couple different strikes
here it's like two different strangles
but that's kind of what I'm betting on
tomorrow that this $855 Cent premium is
going to come in and I'm hoping that the
Tesla news is kind of a non-event and
I'm hoping that it stays inside the
expected move of $14 and if Tesla is
inside of $14 on the opening tomorrow
this strangle will probably trade down
around you know somewhere around $6 and
half dollars to six to6 and a half
dollars is my guess and that is a play
now when you look here you can see the
Greeks I mean this is the probability of
profit on this trade that I have on 82%
which obviously I like the probability
of making 50% well it's a little bit
misleading but it's 88% misleading only
because I'm I'm not going to hold it
that long the Deltas are basically flat
and the beta weighted Deltas are
basically flat and you know when you
when you look at different things one of
the nice things on the tasty platform is
we also show you sear what happens in
the worst 5% of all cases so if you were
to do this as kind of a one lot this
would be your sear which means because a
lot of people like well what's the worst
damn case well this is the only platform
that kind of shows that to you because
it's hard to give you a worst casee
scenario on an undefined risk trade but
I like trades with defined profitability
and undefined risk because we give you
sear so in this case Max profit is 855
kind of this isn't Max risk but this is
the most likely risk of about $77,000
with an 82% probability of profit that's
the kind of trade that I like and
hopefully Tony that kind of makes sense
it's a non-directional trade it's just
playing hey you know what I like these
odds I like the high probability of
profit I like the high implied
volatility I like it wrapped around a
binary event and I like this ratio of
you know of what I think kind of worst
case is in two and a half to 5% of the
time verse what I'm going to make on
kind of just a normal
move um thank you so much for that
breakdown I think we covered a lot of
the things that we talked about before I
do want to cover this concept of sear
and think thinking about this and and
going back to that concept that we're
talking about in terms of law of large
numbers right because um you're
obviously working with a sizable account
here and you can um trade trade
positions of this size but you know
let's think through someone who has
let's say a $50,000 portfolio right sure
let's do this let's do this let's get
rid of this naked option let's get rid
of this delete this leg let's get rid of
this leg we'll delete this leg and let's
let's talk about this let's tighten up
this triangle just so people can see
better so I can see from one screen so
you don't have to look at multiple
scrolling and stuff like that so let's
say that this is the
strangle that somebody had on I'm just
doing it so you can see and you have
limited Capital so that's one choice
obviously is to is to put a position on
like this or you can iron Condor It Off
by just you know buying a wing and you
could put this Wing anywhere you want if
you want to move it you know a bunch of
different strikes you just drag it to
wherever you want I mean just to Define
your risk basically changes the Dynamics
of how much Capital you have to use same
trade it's just a little bit different
synthetically because you're going to
give up some of this some of this
premium as it you know as it evaporates
as well but you still have generally the
same concept
on so you would use the same 45 days you
would use the same strikes in terms of
selecting which ones you sell and you
would use the same method for managing
this
trade I would do everything the exact
same because I would consider this in
this case essentially to be when you do
any kind and and I'm just doing this so
you can see it better we do any kind of
an iron Condor I'm doing it so that so
that um I'm just creating um defining
the risk to create Capital efficiency um
you do hurt your you know you do
depending on where you move it to you
will knock your pop down I would knock
my pop down in this case from like 82 to
like maybe 67% so it changes it changes
um this the probabilistic
outcome and but it also reduces the
Delta risk and you can see here your
cbar goes from let's say 7,000 down to
500 and your max profit only drops in
half so your return on Capital goes
significantly higher but your but your
probability of success goes down the one
thing about options that everybody
listening should should really just
always grasp is they are symmetrically
perfect as far as risk and return goes
we have this thing called put call
parody and because of that and because
of efficient pricing everything works
out the same there's no difference
between the risk you take in doing Trade
A versus the risk you take in doing
trade B it's the mechanics that you use
and how you optimize those mechanics
which is which will determine different
levels of success but if as long as
you're trading a stock like Tesla as an
example you're never going to get
inefficient bad theoreticals or
inefficient pricing every dollar at risk
is going to be virtually the same but
then it's how you tweak manage adjust
close do everything else that really
gives you that optimization and that
efficiency of
optimization I think that's a really
important concept for for a lot of
Traders especially retail traders to
wrap their heads around because what
you're effectively saying is that that
trade before that you showed us with
that had 80s something probability of
profit is no better as a trade than this
trade that only has a 49% probability of
profit I think for a lot of Traders yet
for a lot of Traders you know mentally
speaking it doesn't something with 82%
probability of profit sounds so much
better than something with a 49%
probability of profit and I think that's
a really really sometimes difficult
concept to wrap your head around but um
that is
true and it's really hard to sort of
sometimes explain that but really you
know that the trade with an 82%
probability of profit has a far worse
risk reward ratio than the trade with a
49% probability of profit which has a
far better risk reward ratio and that's
that that counterbalance between risk
reward and probability of profit as what
you're saying is that there's no optimal
um there's no best uh balance if you
will between those two because the
markets are efficient it it doesn't
matter where you are are they they're
kind of all the same if you will it's
it's how you manage the trade that
defines your outcome that's right and
that's why we included sear on the
platform because conditional value at
risk is or some people use value at risk
we use conditional value at risk because
because we set it kind of to a 5% level
but it's really fascinating when you
look at kind of real risk and and you
start to recognize that that's also how
The Regulators view risk at essentially
that 5% level so it's a very Fair number
and it kind of ties this all together
you're right there's no difference as
far as there's no theoretical difference
um with respect to edge of doing this
tight iron Condor versus doing that um
really wide strangle the difference is
in your probabilistic outcome and your
risk reward ratio that's
it well um a lot of insights here today
uh a lot that we've covered um first of
all I want to thank both of you for your
time this has been incredibly insightful
and Incredibly fun honestly just to chat
with both of you and kind of get your
insights with regards to the markets
with regards to your favorite strategies
I had taken the time to take notes here
so that um we will share these uh notes
with everyone after we put up the
recording um but before we wrap up I do
want to just leave uh for everyone who
does not have a tasty trade account if
you want access to the tasty trade
platform that Tom is showing you here
today um you can sign up for a tasty
trade account by going to trade.
optionsplay outcom tastytrade or
pointing your phone to that QR code on
your screen there is a bonus uh at the
moment if you open up your account based
on the levels that you see here on your
screen you'll be able to see the details
of that if you click on that link or go
to uh that um uh that QR code so looking
forward for those of you that are
interested in setting up a tasty trade
account to go ahead and do so um and
once again gentlemen thank you so much
both for your time it's incredibly uh
like I said fun and and and insightful
to to pick both of your brains and
better understand these
strategies thanks thanks Tony and Brian
great to connect again can't wait to do
more of these yes definitely 100% really
enjoyed the time thanks
everybody I think Tom next time we're
going to bring back the think tank and
we're going to go over zero days to
expiration we're going to go over all of
that data that you have I love it love
it man and you know what Tony also we've
been doing a lot of stuff with vix one
day and tying it into the into the zero
day trading and so I've got a lot of
stuff to cover with you on that that'd
be really interesting I think excellent
fantastic thanks guys I will leave I
will leave this link up on the screen uh
I will let everyone take their time out
of the um the room but please thank you
so much gentlemen have a great trading
day and uh we'll see you guys next week